Against the humiliating bondage of a thousand years,
Rapacity came from afar to subjugate them for a hundred years.
Against the cynical malice in the shape,
Of neo-colonialism and its pretty local servants.
Many gave in and certain others resisted.
But the frustrations, the successes, the sweat, the blood,
Have fortified our courageous people and fertilized its heroic struggle.
And one single night has drawn together, the history of an entire people.
And one single night has launched its triumphal march.
Towards the horizon of good fortune, one single night has brought together,
Our people, with all the peoples of the world, in the acquisition of liberty and progress, Motherland or death, we shall conquer!